HENRY M. PACHTER (HEINZ PAECHTER) PAPERS, (GER-071), 1907-1987
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Series 5: Articles Published in Journals, 1929-1987; Undated
  - “The Movement Is the Message.” Clipping, Jan/Feb 1968 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - “The Intellectual as Diplomat.” Clipping, Mar./Apr. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - “Jewish Righteousness and Left-Wing Antisemitism.” Clipping, Spring/Summer 1968 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - “Revisionist Historians and the Cold War.” Clipping, Nov./Dec. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - “Glossen: Nixon vor der amerikanischen Krise.” Clipping, Jan./Feb. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - “The Nixon Regime And Foreign Policy.” Clipping, Jan./Feb. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Classified Military Research and the University: In Response.” Clipping, Jan./Feb. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - “Teaching Negro History.” Clipping, Mar./Apr. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - “Reflections on Unilateral Intervention.” Clipping, May 1969 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - “Der Westen blickt nach Rußland.” Clipping, June 1969 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - “On Being an Exile. An Old-Timer’s Personal and Political Memoir.” Clipping, Fall 1969/Winter 1970. (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - “The Strike at the Free University.” Clipping, Jan. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - “On Re-Reading Hermann Hesse.” Clipping, Spring 1970 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - “Engages Science – or Scientists?” Clipping, July/Aug. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - “The Problem of Imperialism.” Clipping, Sept./Oct. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - “Nazi with a Human Face?” Clipping, Nov./Dec. 1970 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - “Views on Israel.” Clipping, Feb. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - “Willy Brandt Under Fire.” Clipping, June 1971 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - “A Philosophy for the New Left.” Clipping, Fall 1971 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - “The New Shape of Foreign Policy.” Clipping, Oct. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - “Die Legende von Weimar.” Clipping, Nov./Dec. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - “The Intellectuals and the State of Weimar.” Clipping, Summer 1972 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - “Die Ohnmacht der Polizei.” Clipping, May/June 1973 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - “Paul Goodman – A ‘Topian’ Educator.” Clipping, Fall 1973 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - “Gutenberg ist noch nicht tot.” Clipping, Sept./Oct. 1973 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - “When the Government is Lying…” Clipping, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - “Détente – Reality and Myth.” Clipping, Winter 1974 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - “The Idea of Progress in Marxism.” Clipping, Spring 1974 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - “Imperialism in Reverse.” Clipping, June 1974 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - “The Shah of Iran, Is He a Marxist?” Clipping, Summer 1974 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - “Defining an Event: Prolegomenon to Any Future Philosophy of History.” Clipping, Fall 1974 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - “Orthodox Heretic, Romantic Stalinist [George Lukács].” Clipping, Spring 1975 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - “The issue redefined: the Cold War – what was it?” Clipping, May/June 1975 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - “The Private Lives of Rebels.” Clipping, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - “Who are the Palestinians?” Clipping, Fall 1975 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - “Heidegger and Hitler. The Incompatability [!] of Geist and Politics.” Clipping, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - “Nostalgia and Revision: The Vogue of Weimar Culture.” Clipping, Summer 1976 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - “The Revolt of the French ‘New Philosophers’.” Typescript, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - “Was Weimar Necessary?” Clipping, Winter 1977 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - “Requiem For A National Socialist [from Weimar Études].” Clipping, Summer/Fall 1977 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - “Foreword” [to The Letters of Rosa Luxemburg]. Clipping, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - “What Do We Ask of Eurocommunism?” Clipping, Winter 1978 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - “Gershom Scholem – the Myth of the Mythmaker.” Typescript, Winter 1978 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - “Freedom, Authority, Participation.” Clipping, Summer 1978 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - “Aggression as Cultural Rebellion: The German Example.” Clipping, Summer 1978 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - “Ghosts of the Cold War.” Clipping, Fall 1978 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - “Letters: The Politics of Anti-Realism.” Clipping, Winter 1979 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - “Masters of Cultural History II: Friedrich Meinecke and the Tragedy of German Liberalism.” Clipping, Winter 1979 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - "Paris (post World War II) Looks at Berlin (pre World War I).” Clipping, Apr. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - “Thoughts About Stokie.” Clipping, Spring 1979 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - “Unfair to Marx.” Clipping, Summer 1979 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - “Marx and the Jews.” Clipping, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - “Masters of Cultural History III: Johan Huizinga – The Historian as Magister Ludi.” Clipping, Fall 1979 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - “Walther Rathenau. Musil’s Arnheim or Mann’s Naphta? Clipping, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - “Introduction” [Social Research]. Clipping, Spring 1980 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - “Yekkes and Ostjuden: Conflicting Words in the Germany of My Youth.” Clipping, 29366 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - “Brecht’s Personal Politics.” Clipping, Summer 1980 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - “Lewis Mumford – American Savonarola?” Clipping, Summer 1980 (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - “On Germans and Jews.” Clipping, Fall 1980 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - “After Afghanistan – Round Three.” Clipping, Fall 1980 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - “In Response to George Steiner.” Clipping, Fall 1980/Winter 1981 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - “Response: History In America.” Clipping, Fall 1980/Winter 1981 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - “Again: Marx and the Jews.” Clipping, Spring 1981 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - “The Ambiguous Legacy of Eduard Bernstein.” Clipping, Spring 1981 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - “The Radical Émigré in the Metropolis.” Clipping, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - “Theorien und Ideologen.” Clipping, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - “Images of the New Life.” Typescript, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - “Ghosts of the Cold War.” Clipping, Fall 1987 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - “The Economics of Fascist Rule.” Typescript, Undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - “The Idea of Progress in Marxism.” Reprint, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Der Kampf der Generationen.” Reprint, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - “Kommunismus und Klasse.” Photocopy, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - “Stages of Totalitarian Economy.” Reprint, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Margaret Scotford Archer / Salvador Giner: Contemporary Europe. Review. Offprint, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Paul A. Baran / Paul M. Sweezy: Monopoly Capital: An Essay on the American Economic and Social Order. Review. Clipping, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Karl Dietrich Bracher: The German Dictatorship. Review. Clipping, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joseph Buttinger: Am Beispiel Österreichs. Review. Clipping, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Joan Campbell: The German Werkbund. Review. Clipping, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Stephen F. Cohen: Bukharin and the Bolshevik Revolution. Review. Photocopy, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Charles Delzell: Mussolini’s Enemies. Review. Clipping, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Edward E. Ericson: Radicals in the University. Review. Clipping, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Louis Fischer: Russia’s Road from Peace to War. Review. Clipping, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Philipp Frank: Das Kausalgesetz und sein Grenzen. Review. Clipping, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Erich Fromm: The Sane Society. Review. Clipping, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Peter Gay: Freud, Jews and Other Germans; John Murray Cuddihy: The Ordeal of Civility. Review. Clipping, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Antonio Gramsci: Gramsci – Stalinist Without Dogma. Review. Clipping, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Alexander Heard: The Costs of Democracy. Review. Clipping, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Richard Hiscocks: Democracy in Western Germany; Leonard Krieger: The German Idea of Freedom. Review. Clipping, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Peter Hoffmann: The History of the German Resistance 1933-1945. Review. Clipping, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Chang Tu Hu: China: Its People, Its Society, Its Culture. Review. Clipping, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Rodney W. Jones: Urban Politics in India. Review. Clipping, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Douglas Keller: “Korsch’s Revolutionary Historicism.” Review. Clipping, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - George F. Kennan: Memoirs 1929-1950. Review. Clipping, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Donald Peterson Kent: The Refugee Intellectual. Review. Clipping, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Kurt Kluxen: Vorlesungen zur Geschichtstheorie. Review. Clipping, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Milton Kovner: The Challenge of Coexistence. Review. Clipping, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Walter Laqueur: Weimar – A Cultural History. Review. Clipping, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - J. Lenz: Die 2. Internationale und ihre Erbe. Review. Clipping, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Kurt London: Unity and Contradiction. Review. Clipping, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Emil Lousse: Grundbegriffe der Geschichte. Review. Clipping, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Frank E. and Fritzie P. Manuel: Utopian Thought in the Western World. Review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - William McCord: The Spring Time of Freedom. Review. Clipping, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Florence Miale / Michael Selzer: The Nuremberg Mind. Review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - L. Mosse / M. George: The Crisis of German Ideology. Review. Clipping, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - W. W. Rostow: The Stages of Economic Growth. Review. Clipping, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Trent Schroyer: The Critique of Domination. Review. Clipping, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Franz Seitz / Anatole Dauman: The Tin Drum. Film review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Albert Speer: Inside the Third Reich. Review. Clipping, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Hans Speier / W. Philips Davison: West German Leadership and Foreign Policy. Review. Clipping, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Alfred Stern: Philosophy of History and the Problem of Values. Review. Clipping, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Fritz Stern: Gold and Iron. Review. Clipping, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Hans-Jürgen Syberberg: Hitler, ein Film aus Deutschland. Film review. Clipping, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Hugh Thomas: Cuba: The Pursuit of Freedom; K. S. Karól: Guerrillas in Power. Review. Clipping, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Antonio Vásquez de Espinosa: Compendio y Descripción de las Indias Occidentales. Review. Clipping, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - John Willett: Art and Politics in the Weimar Period 1917-1933. Review. Clipping, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - William Appleton Williams: The Roots of the Modern American Empire. Review. Clipping, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Series 6: Published Newspaper Articles, 1932-1986; Undated
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series, the largest series in the collection, has been kept in its original order, as received from Pachter’s estate. His contributions to German and American newspapers are arranged in folders by topic. In many cases, only a copy of the published article is present in the folder, however typescripts of some articles are also included in the folders. This series, which contains over 7,000 items, demonstrates not only the prolific nature of Pachter’s journalistic career, but also the vast range of topics he addressed in his writings.
  - Alphabetical folder listing. Typescript, Undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Adenauer., 1948-1967 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Administration, 1949-1972 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Africa, 1952-1970 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Alaska, Puerto Rico, Hawaii, 1954-1967 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - The American Mind, 1950-1971 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - American in Europe, Europeans in America, 1950-1970 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Antarctic, Arctic, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Anti-Communism, 1949-1962 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Art, the Arts, 1950-1973 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Asia, SEATO, ANZUS, Indonesia, Australia, Philippines, 1951-1971 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Atomic Energy (International), 1953-1969 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Atomic Energy (National)., 1950-1958 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Atomic Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Atomic Tests, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Austria, 1955-1962 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Automation, 1951-1971 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Automobile, 1948-1970 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Aviation, 1950-1964 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Big Deal, 1949-1966 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Biographies, A – K, 1950-1976 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Biographies, L – Z., 1950-1976 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Bomb, 1949-1970 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Budget., 1949-1960 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Business Administration, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Canada, 1951-1970 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Chemical Industry, 1949-1962 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - China, 1949-1972 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Cities, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Civil Liberties, 1949-1977 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Climate, Water, Conservation, 1951-1971 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Colonies, Satellites, Colonialism, 1952-1974 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Commerce, Sales, Advertising, Trade, 1949-1963 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Communications, 1957-1964 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Communism, 1949-1972 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Congress, 1949-1979 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Conservatism, 1952-1971 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Constitution, 1949-1970 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Consumer Goods, Consumer Credits, Services, Savings, 1948-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Corporations, 1950-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cotton, Wool, 1950-1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Country, 1948-1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Crime and Courts, 1949-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cuba, 1952-1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Defense, 1949-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Defense, 1960-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Defense Industries, 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Democrats, 1952-1973 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Disarmament, 1949-1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Displaced Persons, 1950-1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Economic Policy, 1948-1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Economy (Konjunktur), 1948-1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Economy (Konjunktur), 1957-1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Education, 1949-1975 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Eisenhower, 1949-1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Elections, 1948-1963 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Elections, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - England, 1951-1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Europe, 1949-1973 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Family, 1954-1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Farming, 1949-1966 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Food, 1948-1961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Foreign Aid, Point Four, 1948-1971 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Foreign Economic Policy, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Foreign Military Aid, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Foreign Policy (Dulles), 1948-1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Foreign Policy (Dulles), 1957-1961 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Policy (Kennedy; Johnson)., 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Policy (Nixon), 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Trade, 1949-1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Foundations, 1955-1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - France, 1952-1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Free Enterprise, 1948-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - German Property, 1948-1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1949-1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1961-1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Germany, German Affairs, 1966-1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Goldwater, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Great Society, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Greece, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - History, 1954-1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - History, 1964-1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Housing, 1949-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Humphrey, 1958-1968 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Immigration, 1950-1961 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Income, 1951-1963 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - India, 1952-1973 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Indochina, 1954-1971 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - International Court, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Investments, 1952-1962 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Japan, 1950-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Jews, 1960-1980 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Johnson, 1949; 1963-1973 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Kennedy, 1957-1966 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Kennedy Assassination, 1963-1969 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - The Kennedy's, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Korea, 1950-1969 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Labor, Trade Unions, Social Services, 1948-1972 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Language, 1949-1971 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Latin America, 1950-1974 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Left, Liberals, Intellectuals, 1947-1967 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Literature, 1949-1974 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Literature (not by H.P.), 1949-1967 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Lobbies, 1965; 1971 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Managers, 1945-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - McCarthy, Joseph, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - McNamara, Robert, 1960-1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Medacine, 1950-1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Melting Pot, 1951-1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Metals, Raw Materials, Diamonds, Steel, 1950-1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Middle East, India, Pakistan, Afghanistan, Persia, 1949-1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Minorities, 1950-1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950-1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Money, 1948-1968 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Monopoly, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Movies, 1949-1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Music, Dance, 1947-1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - NATO, 1949-1970 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Near East, Palestine, 1951-1963 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Near East, Palestine, 1964-1973 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Negroes, 1964-1971 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Neo-Isolationism, 1965-1971 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Neutralism, Isolationism, Pacifism, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - New Left, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - New York City, 1949-1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Nixon, 1954-1974 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Oil, Coal, Gas, 1949-1974 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Pacifism, 1960-1973 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Panama, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Peace Corps., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Peace Offensive, Big Four, 1951-1966 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Planning, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Popular culture, 1949-1978 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Popular Trends, 1951-1965 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Poverty, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Power, 1951-1958 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Press, 1949-1973 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Propaganda, Terror, Professional Warfare, 1949-1971 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Radioactivity, 1954-1963 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Railroads, Shipping, 1956-1966 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Reaction, 1948-1971 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Religion, 1949-1971 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Republicans, 1948-1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Russia, 1949-1959 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Russia, 1960-1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Science, 1951-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Security, 1949-1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Share Holders, 1952-1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Small Business, 1949-1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Social Services, 1949-1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Socialism, 1949-1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sociology, 1951-1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Space, 1952-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Spain, 1932-1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952-1965 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Stock Market, 1949-1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Summaries, 1948-1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Summit Conference, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Taxes, 1954-1974 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Technique, Technology, Technocracy, 1951-1960 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Television, Radio, 1948-1968 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Textile, 1950-1960 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Theater, 1949-1972 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Truman, 1948-1971 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Trusts, 1949-1962 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Unemployment, 1949-1965 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - United Nations, 1949-1957 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - United Nations, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - United Nations, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - United Nations, 1966-1975 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Vatican, 1951-1970 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Vietnam, 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Vietnam, 1967-1973 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Vietnam peace talks, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Weimar, 1965-1979 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Wheat, 1948-1963 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Women, 1950-1972 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Youth, 1956-1972 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Yugoslavia, 1951-1970; 1986 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Series 7: Audio Tapes and Oversized Materials, 1984; Undated
  The audio tapes include one reel-to-reel tape labeled Dissent, an interview with Pachter about Hannah Arendt, two cassettes (1 side each) of “Heinz Pachter – Gedenken I and II,” and two cassettes (4 sides) of Pachter’s Memoirs of an Exile. Memoirs of an Exile Tape 1 begins with Weimar on side one and side two features the end of Weimar/beginning of Spain. The second tape begins with France/Spain and finishes with Spain on the second side. The folders contain proofs of Socialism in History.
  - Socialism in History Page Proofs, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Dissent, Undated (Reel 1)
  - Interview of Heinz Pachter about Hannah Arendt, Undated (Cassette 1)
  - Heinz Pachter. Gedenken I and II, Undated (Cassette 2-3)
  - Heinz Pachter reading a text on Bukarin, Undated (Cassette 4)
  - Heinz Pachter. Memoirs of an Exile, Undated (Cassette 5-6)